<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>MrAI</title><link>https://themrai.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on MrAI</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://themrai.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The French Foreign Legion fast</title><link>https://themrai.github.io/contemplation/legion/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://themrai.github.io/contemplation/legion/</guid><description>My short experience with the French Foreign Legion.</description></item><item><title>Continuity tester</title><link>https://themrai.github.io/tinkering/continuity_tester/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://themrai.github.io/tinkering/continuity_tester/</guid><description>A simple continuity tester, which you don&amp;rsquo;t have to turn on or off, it is nearly instantaneous in its response and can be used without fear of accidentally destroying it, because of the built in safety features.</description></item><item><title>Bench vice restoration</title><link>https://themrai.github.io/tinkering/bench_vice/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://themrai.github.io/tinkering/bench_vice/</guid><description>Restoring a little bench vice found at the bottom of the junk pile.</description></item><item><title>Turtle ramp</title><link>https://themrai.github.io/tinkering/turtle_ramp/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://themrai.github.io/tinkering/turtle_ramp/</guid><description>Making a little ramp for my red-eared slider to help her egg laying process.</description></item><item><title>3D printer beginner filaments</title><link>https://themrai.github.io/tinkering/3d_printer_beginner_filaments/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://themrai.github.io/tinkering/3d_printer_beginner_filaments/</guid><description>A beginners experiences with the two basic filaments for FFD printers. On PLA, PETG and moisture. If you are a first time 3D printer buyer and are faced with the decision on which filament to buy and why, this is the post for you.</description></item><item><title>Headphone holder</title><link>https://themrai.github.io/tinkering/headphone_stand/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://themrai.github.io/tinkering/headphone_stand/</guid><description>Reclaim some space from your table by putting your headphone where it is still in reach, but not in the way.</description></item><item><title>Roach</title><link>https://themrai.github.io/tinkering/roach/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://themrai.github.io/tinkering/roach/</guid><description>Ever wanted to have a little robot that is so clumsy it is almost fun to watch? Here is my first attempt at doing just that.</description></item><item><title>The Book on the Taboo Against Knowing Who You Are - Alan Watts</title><link>https://themrai.github.io/contemplation/book_1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://themrai.github.io/contemplation/book_1/</guid><description>If you have ever wondered what you are doing with your life. Had the sneaking suspicion that something isn&amp;rsquo;t right. Especially if you are tired of the hustle culture, of gurus selling programs that claim solve your problems. This book may be for you. It talks about religion and faith, goals and motivations, but not as an end all be all. It only gently shows you a way of thinking, that as I did, you may find as a refreshing drop of sanity to center yourself by.</description></item><item><title>Table fan stand</title><link>https://themrai.github.io/tinkering/table_fan/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://themrai.github.io/tinkering/table_fan/</guid><description>Air conditioners are expensive and it is hot outside and you got a lot of 12cm axial fans laying around? This stunningly simple stand can hold the little fan aimed right at you, providing some much needed airflow, while still being extremely quiet.</description></item><item><title>Forced and voluntary feedback</title><link>https://themrai.github.io/contemplation/feedback/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://themrai.github.io/contemplation/feedback/</guid><description>Company cultures are not necessarily healthy, even with the best of intentions. Non the less they are one of the most prevalent aspects of our lives. If we don&amp;rsquo;t watch out, the mistakes in them can seep into our lives, potentially ruining it. Here we examine a way on how not to give feedback and how to do it properly. If ever in doubt try to ask yourself: &amp;lsquo;Is this how I would communicate an issue to my significant other?&amp;rsquo; If not, you know it isn&amp;rsquo;t right. To further help the reader some context and an attempt at explanation is given as well.</description></item><item><title>Longest Common Subsequence</title><link>https://themrai.github.io/algorithms/longest_common_subsequence/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://themrai.github.io/algorithms/longest_common_subsequence/</guid><description>How to solve the &amp;rsquo;longest common subsequence&amp;rsquo; problem. Here we examine a method for solving it recursively (naively) and how to solve it efficiently with dynamic programming.</description></item><item><title>Most useful piece of plastic</title><link>https://themrai.github.io/tinkering/bit_of_plastic/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://themrai.github.io/tinkering/bit_of_plastic/</guid><description>How to make a simple laptop stand for comfort and increased airflow.</description></item><item><title>Dynamic programming</title><link>https://themrai.github.io/algorithms/dynamic_programming/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://themrai.github.io/algorithms/dynamic_programming/</guid><description>An advanced way for designing solutions. What features does a problem need to display so that this type of solution can be applied? If those are satisfied we can transform algorithms with exponential time complexity to polynomial ones, by sacrificing on space.</description></item><item><title>Kadane`s algorithm</title><link>https://themrai.github.io/algorithms/kadane/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://themrai.github.io/algorithms/kadane/</guid><description>A brilliant way for solving the maximal subsequence problem (or maximal sub-array). One of those specialized algorithms that makes you truly appreciate the genius of others'.</description></item></channel></rss>