<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tinkering on MrAI</title><link>https://themrai.github.io/tinkering/</link><description>Recent content in Tinkering on MrAI</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://themrai.github.io/tinkering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Headphone holder</title><link>https://themrai.github.io/tinkering/headphone_stand/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://themrai.github.io/tinkering/headphone_stand/</guid><description>Problem For the longest time, my headphone was taking up space on my table. I don&amp;rsquo;t use it all the time, but I do sit at my table for work and for leisure and when I happen to not listen to music I need space to work.
It would be nice if I could put the headphone to an easily accessible place, but not on the workspace.
Design So what can be done?</description></item><item><title>Most useful piece of plastic</title><link>https://themrai.github.io/tinkering/bit_of_plastic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://themrai.github.io/tinkering/bit_of_plastic/</guid><description>Fusion 360 link: laptop_stand
Not all projects need to be complicated. In fact this one was one of the simplest of all, but it solves a real problem, and for that I appreciate it very much.
My laptop, a Lenovo T14 Gen 2, as a good deal of modern equipment today advertised towards the business costumer (despite its ~2500 EUR price-tag at the time of writing) tends to heat up quite a bit after a little while.</description></item><item><title>Roach</title><link>https://themrai.github.io/tinkering/roach/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://themrai.github.io/tinkering/roach/</guid><description>The first idea For a while now I wanted to have a tiny little robot that would just roam around the room, without much purpose and try to mimic some behavior, that would make it somewhat amusing to look at.
Now, since I know very little about electronics, I wanted to set the initial goal very low. So you know it can actually be achieved. I could imagine an awesome little spider-bot, but couldn&amp;rsquo;t really build it.</description></item><item><title>Table fan stand</title><link>https://themrai.github.io/tinkering/table_fan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://themrai.github.io/tinkering/table_fan/</guid><description>Problem Summers are hot where I live, and even though I have a big fan that moves more than enough air to provide help my body enough with its evaporative cooling, it has one problem. It is more than enough. It moves too much air, and it is loud compared to what I need.
In the empire of dirt there is an abundance of 12 cm diameter radial cooling fans. These are usually optimized to move as much air and as quietly as possible.</description></item></channel></rss>