<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Contemplation on MrAI</title><link>https://themrai.github.io/contemplation/</link><description>Recent content in Contemplation on MrAI</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://themrai.github.io/contemplation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Forced and voluntary feedback</title><link>https://themrai.github.io/contemplation/feedback/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://themrai.github.io/contemplation/feedback/</guid><description>In this essay my aim is to highlight flaws in how corporations are implementing feedback sessions, how these can be mitigated and in general what should we watch out for while doing so. To prepare the reader for what may come, many ideas/opinions might strike the reader as painful, ridiculous or even rage inducing. When this occurs please try to understand the points before dismissing them entirely. You may not agree at all, but there is always something that can be gained from an argument.</description></item><item><title>The Book on the Taboo Against Knowing Who You Are - Alan Watts</title><link>https://themrai.github.io/contemplation/book_1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://themrai.github.io/contemplation/book_1/</guid><description>Refreshingly Alan Watts has an easy to read and follow writing style, and contrary to how verbose similar books usually are, it is short and to the point.
The following writing goes through the chapters of the book and tries to summarize it in a way I have understood it. This interpretation may be completely wrong and for that it should be taken with a grain of salt. However, I think it will be helpful to those who are contemplating buying the book as it can provide a short summary in what may be found within the pages.</description></item></channel></rss>